

JAVIER LOPEZ GALACHE

Demand Planner Full Stack Developer

Superi 2176, Buenos Aires, 1430, Argentina

+54 11 33831405 jaloga93@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 07-08-1993 Nationality: Argentinean

Place of Birth: Buenos Aires

LINKS

Linkedin, GitHub

PROFILE

Forward thinking young Full Stack Developer, industrial engineering student with 5+ years working experience in the IT field. Proven record of success coordinating cross-dock logistic operations working with ERP systems under dynamic environments. (SAP ERP key-user for the region). Enthusiastic on driving customer-focused process improvements and implementations. Designed BenderOnline web platform, handling backend SQL relational tables with phpMyAdmin to store both server-side data and client-side data. Minimalistic approaches for Frontend design.

Areas of Expertise:

DEMAND PLANNING:

ERP:

SAP (PR3/4, HELIOS, APO)

SKILLS:

Statistical Forecasting KPI analysis Continuous Improvement

PROGRAMMING:

JavaScript:

React, Express, Next.JS, Node.JS

Python:

Flask, Django, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciKit Tools.

Databases:

MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase.

Frontend:

CSS3, Tailwind CSS

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full Stack Engineer | Owner, iTeams Platform

Buenos Aires

(Feb 2021 — Present)

Founder of iTeamsPlatform.com. New proyect focused on eLearing based on the community's collab amongst each other. In charge of adapting the ERD design, nonSQL database modelling and CRUD setup focused on the organization's business model.

Full Stack Developer, BenderOnline.com

Buenos Aires

(Aug 2020 — Present)

In charge of developing the whole web application for a private business project. Apache, MariaDB, phpMyAdmin, python, Flask, React, JS/Jquery, CSS3 and Bootstrap. Created backend SQL relational tables with phpMyAdmin to store both server-side data and client-side data.

Senior Demand Planner & Finished Goods Planner | Signify

(Aug 2019 — Mar 2020)

Buenos Aires

Onboarding Professional Lighting Systems demand and supply planning for Chile and Peru.

Finished Goods & Demand Planner, Philips Lighting

(Jan 2018 — Aug 2019)

Buenos Aires

Managing Demand and Supply Planning for Argentina, Uruguay, Paraguay and Bolivia. In charge of import & export logistics operations. Cross-dock operations. Assembly of local produced products. QxP forecast. Reported Sales and Operations to Board in a monthly basis, exposing financial forecasts, risks and building blocks for the quartile. In charge of sharing the products volume intake to Factories to align Supply and Demand. Handled communications with more than 25 Factories from more than 10 countries.

EDUCATION

Buenos Aires

Industrial Engineering

Buenos Aires

CS50x Introduction to Computer Science (https://certificates.cs50.io/4be132c6-a2f1-4733-bb56-4008209b6ea5.pdf?size=letter)

Buenos Aires

Procurement, Stock and Supply Certification

Buenos Aires

Ingenieria Informática

SKILLS

Communication	SkillsI	Exper	ienced
---------------	---------	-------	--------

Ability to Work Under Pressure......Expert

Ability to Work in a Team......Expert

Microsoft Office & VBA......Expert

CSS.....Experienced

HTML.....Expert

SQL.....Experienced

Git.....Experienced

Python.....Experienced

Javascript.....Skillful

LANGUAGES

English	Highly Proficient
Spanish	Native Speaker
French	Δ2